<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>My Notes</title>
    <description>These are my notes.</description>
    <link>https://celineyuwonodiary.github.io//</link>
    <atom:link href="https://celineyuwonodiary.github.io//sitemap.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 19 Nov 2020 21:06:26 +0900</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Nov 2020 21:06:26 +0900</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.9.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Do I Find God's Will for My Life?</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;purpose-vs-calling&quot;&gt;Purpose vs Calling&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Purpose&lt;/strong&gt;: Your purpose is the reason you are created. The only way to know why you are created is to ask the creator. Everyone has a unique purpose. Examples include teaching the gospel, building infrastructure in remote areas, or establishing a health-care business to promote healthy living. The end goal is ultimately to make disciples of Christ.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The human body has many parts, but the many parts make up one whole body. So it is with the body of Christ (1 Corinthians 12:12)&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Calling&lt;/strong&gt;: Your calling is when God tells you to do something specific in a certain period of time. God may call you to go Med School or write a book. A calling is not an end goal, but it is what builds your character that leads you to fulfiling your purpose. We may share the same calling, but our purpose will be different.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you are obedient to God and follow what God calls you to do, you will be walking in your purpose and in there you will truly realize and live out your passion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;And we know that all things work together for good to those who love God, to those who are the called according to His purpose (Romans 8:28).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;three-types-of-calling&quot;&gt;Three Types of Calling&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The General Call&lt;/strong&gt;: This is God’s first call to us to become Christians.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Call of Marriage&lt;/strong&gt;: Marriage is when God joins two people in covenant. This is a special type of calling because when you are called to take a job, you can change jobs, but when you marry, you are bound to it until death.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Continuous Calling&lt;/strong&gt;: This calling is a process consisting of multiple callings where in each step, God leads you into positions of service in order for you to grow. These positions of service can be in Church or in the Marketplace.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;finding-your-calling&quot;&gt;Finding Your Calling&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Delight yourself in the Lord, and he will give you the desires of your heart (Psalms 37:4).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are you being obedient to God? Your can check if your calling is from God and if it is where God wants you to be by going through the 6 questions below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What kinds of services are good and beneficial?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What are the true needs of the world?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What has God gifted me to be fruitful at?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What are the counsel I receive from godly people?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Am I covering all of this in constant prayer for ?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What are my recurring, strong, holy desires?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;bible-verse-of-the-day&quot;&gt;Bible Verse of the Day&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Therefore go and make disciples of all nations, baptizing them in the name of the Father and of the Son and of the Holy Spirit, and teaching them to obey everything I have commanded you. And surely I am with you always, to the very end of the age (Matthew 28:19-20).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We must imitate Christ and set an example of what it is like to live in God, in order to gather disciples of Christianity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;references&quot;&gt;References&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=C-WNcQAK1AI&quot;&gt;5 Lies About “Knowing Your Purpose” | How to Find Your Purpose&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=u-LvOF4BNGA&quot;&gt;How Do I Find God’s Will for My Life? // Ask Pastor John&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2019 22:31:00 +0900</pubDate>
        <link>https://celineyuwonodiary.github.io//bible/2019/12/09/how-do-i-find-will.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://celineyuwonodiary.github.io//bible/2019/12/09/how-do-i-find-will.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>Bible</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Agile Development Methodology: Scrum</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;traditional-vs-agile-software-development-methodologies&quot;&gt;Traditional vs. Agile Software Development Methodologies&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.pinimg.com/originals/bc/89/69/bc896937201b696beef56feb1c4adb19.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Agile/Scrum vs Traditional/Waterfall&quot; width=&quot;500px&quot; display=&quot;inline-block&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://coeleveld.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/scrum-vs-traditional.png&quot; alt=&quot;Scrum vs Traditional Methodology&quot; width=&quot;400px&quot; display=&quot;inline-block&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In traditional software development, a team follows through the traditional SDLC starting from planning, analysis, design, implementation, testing, implementation, and maintenance within a longer period of time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Agile Methodology is basically iterative development meaning that instead of taking up a year or so and following a full SDLC cycle, a team follows through a certain framework to develop features or programs within a short period of time called a sprint. A new sprint begins once the previous one ends and the resulting product of each sprint are finished, usable features.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the traditional software development methodology focuses on the end product, agile methodology breaks down the end product into independent features and develop those in iterations. This allows for a change in course in development if the product specification changes allowing better accomodation of the customer’s needs, hence the term ‘agile’. In the agile methodology, the team focuses on results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-framework-of-agile-scrum&quot;&gt;A Framework of Agile: Scrum&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://image.slidesharecdn.com/mobileacademyagilelean-140518125420-phpapp01/95/agile-and-lean-practices-the-mobile-academy-12-638.jpg?cb=1400562822&quot; alt=&quot;Scrum Framework&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember that agile is only a methodology, or a way of thinking. There are multiple frameworks that has structure and rules to developing a software the agile method. One of it is called the Scrum.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Three Types of Roles&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Product Owner&lt;/strong&gt;: The Product Owner gets input from the customers and knows the big picture of what the product should be. They are responsible in defining the end goal and the tasks that needs to be completed to the rest of the team. The Product Owner creates the backlog of to-do list items and reviews deliverables before the product is delivered.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scrum Master:&lt;/strong&gt; The scrum master can be said to be the project manager. They oversee day-to-day functions and check-in with the members of the development team. They are reponsible for the tasks to be delivered on time and the team’s wellbeing.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Team Member:&lt;/strong&gt; Team members are engineers, copywriters, designers, and so on of the development team. They focus on developing high quality products.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Common Types of Meetings in a Scrum&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Daily Scrum:&lt;/strong&gt; Scrum master and development team report what they did, what they are going to do, or difficulties daily in a short meeting. The meeting should be light and ideally be no longer than 15 minutes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sprint Planning:&lt;/strong&gt; This is one big meeting at the end of each sprint where finished products are reviewed, and new tasks are divided marking the beginning of the next sprint. The product owner needs to prepare which tasks in the backlog to prioritize and define the requirements to the scrum master and development team in order for the right amount of tasks to be divided properly. This meeting should last no more than 4 hours for a 2 week sprint.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sprint Review:&lt;/strong&gt; The meeting where the development team presents to the product manager and scrum master what they did during the sprint. In the case of multiple teams in a project, a representative of the team can present. It shuold last for 2 hours for a 2 week sprint.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sprint Retrospective:&lt;/strong&gt; A meeting consisting of the scrum master and development team to reflect on the previous sprint and what each member of the team felt they did well, difficulties along the way, and what could be done for improvement. The meeting should last between 1-2 hours for a 2 week sprint.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Backlog Refining:&lt;/strong&gt; In this meeting, members of the development team estimates how long to finish a task in the backlog so the product owner can decide on which task to prioritize in each sprint.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-key-to-making-agile-development-work&quot;&gt;The Key to Making Agile Development Work&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Each role of the agile development must be defined so that everyone understands what is expected of them and deliver those expectations.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Product requirements must be clearly determined so that each member of the development team knows what they are responsible of, allowing flexible work but the task still finished on time.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Meetings are important but never go over the necessary meeting time. It is important to know the goal and takeaway of every meeting.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;references&quot;&gt;References&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://redbooth.com/blog/main-roles-agile-team&quot;&gt;The Three Main Roles in an Agile Team&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://softwareengineering.stackexchange.com/questions/15928/what-is-agile-methodology&quot;&gt;What is Agile Methodology?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/ideas-by-crema/the-4-scrum-ceremonies-made-simple-a-quick-guide-to-scrum-meetings-ea91fe604d88&quot;&gt;The 4 Scrum Ceremonies Made Simple&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;images&quot;&gt;Images&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://i.pinimg.com/originals/bc/89/69/bc896937201b696beef56feb1c4adb19.jpg&quot;&gt;Agile/Scrum vs Traditional/Waterfall&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://scontent-nrt1-1.xx.fbcdn.net/v/t1.0-9/14344304_1397070920321959_3431169010133890617_n.png?_nc_cat=109&amp;amp;_nc_ohc=HCZNuErDT4EAQlKI8QEoiEtnuX5aZz6oMb4zKEoIisOg1CNo_spHO1-Tw&amp;amp;_nc_ht=scontent-nrt1-1.xx&amp;amp;oh=4cee1de44034dbf10e88a3b7e79b680b&amp;amp;oe=5E7FDEBC&quot;&gt;Scrum vs Traditional Methodology&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://image.slidesharecdn.com/mobileacademyagilelean-140518125420-phpapp01/95/agile-and-lean-practices-the-mobile-academy-12-638.jpg?cb=1400562822&quot;&gt;Scrum Framework&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2019 18:32:44 +0900</pubDate>
        <link>https://celineyuwonodiary.github.io//projectmanagement/2019/12/05/agile-development-scrum.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://celineyuwonodiary.github.io//projectmanagement/2019/12/05/agile-development-scrum.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>ProjectManagement</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Introduction to Cloud Computing</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-is-cloud-computing&quot;&gt;What is Cloud Computing?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the needs of a company changes, the company’s software, hardware, and information resources needs will also change. A company might need to scale-up and use a faster computing system with a larger database. On the other hand, a company may need to scale-down and use a simpler system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the traditional on-premise IT infrastructure, it is hard for a business to scale-up or down. A company that needs to scale-up will need to upgrade its IT Infrastructure, which takes time and money. In contrast, scaling-down means not being able to use their IT Infrastructure optimally and paying for unused resources.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cloud computing allows companies to simply connect and use resources stored in virtual data centers via the internet. The companies will only have to pay to use these resources at a pay per use basis. This on-demand system saves companies time and money, and makes it very easy for a company to scale-up or down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;three-deployment-models-of-cloud-computing&quot;&gt;Three Deployment Models of Cloud Computing&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.cloudflare.com/resources/images/slt3lc6tev37/2jBaVWKgbOUNLDNw7QJYPh/563316b4290e2919f7510ae59a3ae3ca/public-cloud-vs-private-cloud.svg&quot; alt=&quot;Private Cloud vs Public Cloud&quot; width=&quot;750px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Private Cloud&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a Private Cloud, the cloud server is only managed by one company and maintained in a private network. It is highly secure and is best for companies that handle sensitive data like the government. The server can be stored on-premise or hosted, but is commonly stored on-premises in the company’s data center. Private cloud providers include IBM Cloud Private and Liquid Web. A company has to pay for maintenance costs only for on-premise Private Cloud and not on a hosted Private Cloud. An on-premise Private Cloud can be compared to a traditional on-premise IT infrastructure, where these two terms differ is that the former is a deployment model and the latter refers to the location of the server.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Public cloud&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A Public Cloud means that the cloud infrastructure is made available to the general public and is owned by cloud service providers like AWS and Azure. This is the most commonly used cloud deployment model. It is off-site and a server may be shared between multiple companies, also called multi-tenancy. It has a lower upfront cost with a pay as you go model, making it a flexible option. Most businesses use this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hybrid cloud&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hybrid Cloud uses both private and public clouds. Companies may use services from multiple cloud providers and this is called multi cloud, but many cloud providers also provide the hybrid cloud service. It is efficient because companies can choose which cloud to store their resources in depending the type of resource.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;three-cloud-computing-service-models-pyramid-form&quot;&gt;Three Cloud Computing Service Models (Pyramid Form)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mycloudblog7.files.wordpress.com/2013/06/screen-shot-2015-06-09-at-2-13-05-pm1.png?w=780&amp;amp;h=372&quot; alt=&quot;Differences between IaaS, PaaS, and SaaS&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Infrastructure as a Service (IaaS)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In an IaaS, the company has entire control over the IT infrastructure, including the application, data, runtime, and middleware. Target users are system administrators and network architects. The company has no control over the virtual environment where the operating system runs in. Examples of IaaS are AWS EC2 and S3.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pros:&lt;/strong&gt; Cloud provides Infrastructure, enhanced scalability.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cons:&lt;/strong&gt; Security issues, network delays, needs staff to maintain the infrastructure.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Platform as a Service (PaaS)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For Paas, the development environment, operating system, web server, and database is provided by the vendor. This means that developers can build, compile, and run their programs without worrying about the underlying infrastructure. Examples of Paas are Red Hat, AWS Elastic Beanstalk, and Heroku.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pros:&lt;/strong&gt; Cost effective and scalable, faster market for developers, easy deployment of web applications.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cons:&lt;/strong&gt; Developers limited to providers’ language and tools, migration issues.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Software as a Service (SaaS)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SaaS is ready to use application that is accessible in the browser via the internet. The target users are the average end user of a web application like you and me. With SaaS, there is no need to install a software on PC, and one software is available for use by multiple users.
Examples of SaaS includes Gmail, Google Docs, and Salesforce.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pros:&lt;/strong&gt; Universally available.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cons:&lt;/strong&gt; Internet and browser issues.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;top-cloud-providers&quot;&gt;Top Cloud Providers&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AWS:&lt;/strong&gt; Focuses on mainly on IaaS (EC2, S3) but has PaaS (Elastic Beanstalk).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Microsoft Azure:&lt;/strong&gt; Focuses on AI, analytics, and IoT, Azure Compute and offers services in the category of IaaS (Azure Virtual Machines) and PaaS (Azure App Service - Windows Based). PaaS caters toward Windows-based development.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Google Cloud&lt;/strong&gt;: Offers similar services to Azure, including Iaas (Google Compute Engine) and PaaS (Google App Engine). PaaS caters toward Linux-based development.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;resources&quot;&gt;Resources&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=uYGQcmZUTaw&quot;&gt;Cloud Computing: What is Cloud Computing?&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=1pBuwKwaHp0&quot;&gt;Cloud Computing in the Year 2020&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=36zducUX16w&quot;&gt;Cloud Computing Services Models - IaaS PaaS SaaS Explained&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://searchcloudcomputing.techtarget.com/tip/IaaS-vs-PaaS-options-on-AWS-Azure-and-Google-Cloud-Platform&quot;&gt;IaaS vs. PaaS options on AWS, Azure and Google Cloud Platform&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;images&quot;&gt;Images&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cloudflare.com/resources/images/slt3lc6tev37/2jBaVWKgbOUNLDNw7QJYPh/563316b4290e2919f7510ae59a3ae3ca/public-cloud-vs-private-cloud.svg&quot;&gt;Private Cloud vs Public Cloud&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://mycloudblog7.files.wordpress.com/2013/06/screen-shot-2015-06-09-at-2-13-05-pm1.png?w=780&amp;amp;h=372&quot;&gt;Differences between IaaS, PaaS, and SaaS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2019 12:43:45 +0900</pubDate>
        <link>https://celineyuwonodiary.github.io//cloud/futuretech/2019/12/02/intro-to-cloud-computing.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://celineyuwonodiary.github.io//cloud/futuretech/2019/12/02/intro-to-cloud-computing.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>Cloud</category>
        
        <category>FutureTech</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
